Corinne Krych – +3395 095 13 85 – +336 28 34 61 18 – corinnekrych@gmail.com – 42 chemin des Bastides Villa 2, 06130 Grasse – Date of Birth: 12/02/1972 – French Citizen

Background Summary

Senior technical consultant with 15 years experience, 12 companies, worked in different environments and methodologies. Enthusiastic, curious and skilled.

Pragmatic thinker I will understand requirements and turn them into quality software and useful documentation. http://corinnekrych.github.com

Open source projects & Conferences

ConFESS April 2013	Hybrid Mobile App in minutes Workshop (Speaker)
Greach (Madrid) January 2013	Hybrid mobile app in minutes, not days (Speaker)
Greach (Madrid) January 2013	Building a Groovy DSL with user interaction (Speaker)
Greach (Madrid) January 2013	HTML5 Games Hands-on (Speaker)
Grails eXchange (London) December 2012	User Interaction and Groovy DSL (Speaker)
JS.Everywhere (Paris) November 2012	Hybrid mobile app in minutes not days (Speaker)
GR8 Conf (Copenhagen) June 2012	Building a Groovy DSL (Speaker)
3musket33rs	http://3musket33rs.github.com Grails Mobile plugins suite (Open source development)
RivieraGUG	http://www.rivieragug.org co-founder coolest GUG in France
Mobile apps in minutes November 2012	Groovy Mag (Publication)

Career history

Mobile Open Source Hacker

http://3musket33rs.github.com

3musket33rs Grails Mobile plugins suite provides Mobile HTML5 scaffolding.

- In a minute you can scaffold a skeleton for your mobile application that contains all you need for CRUD operations. Taking Grails MVC a step further remove classical GSP for MV* implementation client side.
- Single page approach in HTML5 with client side widget and validation based on jQuery mobile.
- Using convention over configuration, scaffolding for offline and back online synchronisation.
- Map Service for geolocation
- Server side push notification using Atmosphere SSE implementation
- PhoneGap packaging for Hybrid App

Roadmap:

- plug to any JavaScript MV* framework (TodoMVC)
- make 3musket33rs suite REST implementation agnostic
- package 3musket33rs suite into yeoman
- Android/iOS scaffolding
- multi-user offline implementation

Amadeus (Sophia Antipolis France), Senior Software Engineer

http://www.amadeus.com

March 2009 to Present

Join SellConnect team to develop Productivity Suite:

- design/implement DSL for scripting travel agent's cryptic reservation language using embedded groovy DSL
- implement translator migration (antlr)
- develop web2.0 UI using Aria Templates (http://ariatemplates.com/), first Amadeus Open Source project

Senior developer in Profile team:

- Coach junior team member, define use cases and tasks in a collaborative approach
- Implement OPS (Open Profile Suite) for American Express within aggressive deadlines, bringing new North American market opportunities for Amadeus,
- Initiate pragmatic technical documentation for developers (distributed team Nice and Waltham offices) on OPS business
- Present video conference functional walk-through meetings
- Interface with Profile back end and User Management (LSS) back end team
- Escalate and close follow up on issues, bring topics to architecture board.

Experian – Extelia (Sophia Antipolis France), Senior Consultant

http://www.extelia.fr

October 2008 to February 2009

Part of the « Plateforme Télécollecte » team, working on back office software for transferring and archiving of all administrative

formalities (constitution, radiation etc...) between CFE (government company for formalities) and the court clerks:

- Designed and development of the java batch new platform « Formalités » using the Xml Régent Edi 2008 standard which support previous norms via XSL converter.
- Redesigned « build management system »: modules and dependencies, Maven, Artifactory, unit test strategy based on EasyMock.

Amadeus (Sophia Antipolis France), Senior Software Engineer

http://www.amadeus.com

September 06 to February 08

Member of Software Engineering team (SDX):

- Enhanced development environment: Eclipse plugin packaging, build framework to install products,
- Initiated and maintained a wiki-based knowledge database on 'how to', FAQs and user/installation guides.
- Introduced dependencies management system to migrate monolithic applications into technical and business components using Ivy/Maven frameworks.

UBS (London UK), Senior Software Engineer

http://www.ubs.com

June 05 to May 06

Part of XTools team (development and infrastructure support for Equities IT developers across the world):

- Implemented maven and build system (ant) standards for the java teams.
- Structured Maven 1&2 repositories and maven-HUFS (UBS specific directory structure and deployment process) bridge.
- Introduced a Collaborative Software Development platform for UB IT Equities based on open source GForge product.
- Promoted and advised on best practices for building or refactoring J2EE applications.

Servista (London UK), Technical Team Leader

http://www.servista.com

November 04 to May 05

Servista develops solutions in customer care, billing, marketing and customer analytics. For the 'Operational Service Requests' Swing/Web Start application:

- Coached XP team of 5 developers (Agile methodology) to achieve weekly iteration and integration, automated build running unit test, keep it simple and test-driven approach.
- Liaised with marketing people (Client)
- Liaised with QA team and organize training session with future users.

BACS Limited (London UK), Senior Software Engineer

http://www.voca.co.uk

January 04 to November 04

BACS is the UK's automated clearing-house, which transfers funds between banks for the settlement of payments. As lead developer of the BACSTEL-IP Project:

- Coached the team using Agile methodology to meet tight deadlines.
- Introduced pair programming sessions
- Following a test-driven approach, re-instated unit tests (JUnit, In-container with Cactus and Mock Object)
- added coverage tool (Clover)
- automated incremental build (Cruise Control interfacing with Clear Case) to measure progress.
- Worked with SCM team to redesign ClearCase/ClearQuest to meet Agile approach

Marsh Inc. (Toronto Canada), Senior Software Designer

http://www.marsh.com

Oct 00 to Oct 02

Marsh Inc., world's leading risk and insurance services firm, is dealing with risk management, insurance-broking and programmanagement services. As a member of the e-business applications team, worked on Surety project, web based application to manage surety bond:

- Participated on development of MVC framework using Apache Struts Model for the work-flow, JSP and XML/XSL for the rendering.
- Developed EJB components (stateless session beans and BMP with TopLink) with IBM WebSphere Application Server.
 Migration of legacy CORBA Marsh Business Services.
- Liaised with business analyst team to produce RUP artefacts.

Department of the Solicitor General of Canada (Integrated Justice) (Toronto Canada),

Software Engineer

http://www.publicsafety.gc.ca

Dec 99 to Sept 00

Architectured a platform/language independent middle-ware layer for remote administrative tools through usage of CORBA.

Griechsen Gilchrist Ltd (London - UK), start-up Sep 99 to Oct 99

Prototyped a Java Web application to promote the JTS (Java Transaction Service) of Arjuna (Bluestone/HewletPackward):

Trace Financial plc, (London UK), Developer http://www.tracegroup.com Au 98 to Au 99

Developed new modules for Trafic in C++ for the Standard Settlement Instructions for ICON and OASYS.

Quaternove Paris (Paris France), Designer / Programmer http://www.quaternove.fr Jul 97 to Jul 98

Designed the object oriented model with the case tool **Objecteering (UML** methodology), Developed STD - billing application - for the Public French Electricity (EDF) in **C++**

Maestro: Filial of MATIF S.A Paris (Paris France), Developer

http://www.matif.fr Jan 97 to Jun 97

Maestro IT division of (French future exchange and derivatives market)
Designed and developed with **Visual C++**, Tenor, a front and middle office software for banking application.

Avenir Havas Média, Paris (Paris France) Developer http://www.havas.fr Feb 96 to Dec 96

Designed STRADA (geomarketing application) database, using **MERISE** methodology, GUI implementation with **Delphi**.

Education and Training

April 2004	Sun Certified Web Component Developer for the Java 2 Platform, Enterprise Edition 1.3 (CX-310-080)
March 2003	IBM XML and Related Technologies Certification (test 141)
October 1999	Java2 SUN Certification (310-025)
June 1999	Certificate in Advanced English (CAE) of Cambridge
January 1999	"Informix-OnLine Dynamic Server 6/7 Database Administration"
March 1998	Sybase trainings: "Administration of SQL Server 11", "Transact-SQL System 11.0"
1991 – 1996	E.S.I.E.A. (Paris V) Master's degree in computer services.
1990	Baccalauréat C (French scientific A-level).